<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: programming | Minimaluminiumalism]]></title>
  <link href="http://kailun-wu.github.io/blog/categories/programming/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kailun-wu.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-04-11T20:44:38-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://kailun-wu.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kailun Wu]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mirror of Thoughts]]></title>
    <link href="http://kailun-wu.github.io/blog/programming-thinking/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-08T00:59:52-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://kailun-wu.github.io/blog/programming-thinking</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Programming languages are really close to linguistics, for what we made and use will reshape us. It&rsquo;s been believed that German the language contributes to the abundance of philosophers in Germany. <sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> Steve Jobs, <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/movie/steve-jobs-the-lost-interview/id536749587">back in the 1995</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>We use them (programming) in the work, but much more importantly, it does nothing to do with using them for anything practical. Have to do with using them to be a mirror of your thought process, to actually learn how to think.</p>

<p>I think everybody in this country should learn how to program a computer, should learn a computer language, because it teaches you how to think. It&rsquo;s like going to law school. I don&rsquo;t think everybody should be a lawyer, but I think going to law school may actually be useful coz it teaches you how to think in a certain way. In the same way the computer programming teaches you in a slightly different way how to think. So I view computer science as a liberal arts. It should be something everybody takes in a year in their life, one of the courses they take is learning how to program.</p></blockquote>

<p>Interesting to see how this correlates with <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7Pq-S557XQU">&ldquo;Human needs not apply&rdquo;</a>.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Curiously, ancient Chinese doesn&rsquo;t contain the word &ldquo;is/are/be/etc&rdquo; and “是” is only a recent creation.<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
