<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: keyboard | Artifact]]></title>
  <link href="http://kailun-wu.github.io/blog/categories/keyboard/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kailun-wu.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-30T21:49:02-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://kailun-wu.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kailun Wu]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thoughts on Mechanical Keyboard]]></title>
    <link href="http://kailun-wu.github.io/blog/thoughts-on-mechanical-keyboard/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-25T01:48:57-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://kailun-wu.github.io/blog/thoughts-on-mechanical-keyboard</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m fond of <a href="http://www.douban.com/photos/album/134718709/">mechanical keyboards</a> now (<a href="http://instagram.com/p/r6Hp8tPQI-/">here&rsquo;s mine</a>), which is a surprise to people including myself. To most, those keyboards are relics from the 80s. Everyone now uses a laptop with built-in chiclet keys and a phone with touch keyboard. No one need a dedicated one, period.</p>

<p>But it feels so good. Seldom do I see a product perfectly balancing productivity, design, build quality and personality. Dieter Rams&#8217; 10 principles of good design totally applies here.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> In a very sensible way it&rsquo;s superior to laptop keyboard in every aspect except in size. After all, keyboards have come a long way and the manufacturing process are mature. If &ldquo;personal computer is like bicycle for the mind&rdquo;<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup>, then mechanical keyboard makes bicycles better.</p>

<p>But is mechanical keyboard barely surviving? Is it like nascent personal computers in the 70s, or is it like DSLR cameras today? I&rsquo;ve been thinking about these questions and how it&rsquo;s possible to popularize mechanical keyboards. Without any market research data, I can only draw conclusion from observation.</p>

<p>Personal computing in the 70s are used by pros and has a high price. There&rsquo;re booming brands but more PCs are DIY-ed than integrated. You can&rsquo;t buy what you want and may not realize what you what. Mechanical keyboards today are precisely the same.</p>

<p>Cameras today are being replaced by the best cameras - the ones on your phone with you all day. Granted, phone cameras are <a href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/8/22/6055591/iphone-vs-pro-camera">shittier</a> and professional cameras are still going to be around. But the fact that most people are served by smartphones will erase the need for consumer cameras. Mechanical keyboards today are precisely the same.</p>

<p>My tendency is that keyboard are like cameras. Usually a product would go through different phases in their life. PCs and cameras has gone through all of them: enthusiast phase, professional phase and consumer phase. So do keyboards. Ideally the user base would swell with consumers. But before it becomes mass market the desktop computers themselves were largely replaced by laptops, rendering the consumer portion of mechanical keyboards miniscule. Like game console, which became more advanced and pricier historically and is ceding casual gaming to PCs and smartphones, mechanical keyboard continues to be refined.<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote">3</a></sup> But it lacks stellar new features and don&rsquo;t have popular brands like Beats. So popularizing mechanical keyboard depends on the total user base of personal computing, the percentage of enthusiasts and professionals in that user base, and innovation in design/marketing. Beats enjoys healthy profits from headsets and Sony sells PlayStation 4 faster than they could understand. Likely we can see the same happened to mechanical keyboards as more people on Earth have access to their first computing devices and more people discover the desire for better experience.</p>

<p>Show people the story of how mechanical keyboard can bring them individuality, productivity, ergonomics and creativity. Let them hit keycaps in person. Let them know how long keyboards last. Game junkies, software engineers and designers would be on board but bold design is needed to win average consumers. WASD Keyboards has brought us real keycap customization and HHKB/KBC sells minimalism. New ideas and parts discussed on GeekHack and Deskthority can also be adopted.</p>

<p>People have jobs to be done and if some companies can provide a radical solution and fix the broken status of mechanical keyboard, everyone is doing better.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p><a href="http://www.douban.com/note/77176672/">Said Dieter Rams</a>: &ldquo;Good design is innovative. Good design makes a product useful. Good design is aesthetic. Good design is unobtrusive. Good design makes a product understandable. Good design is honest. Good design is long-lasting. Good design is environmentally-friendly. Good design is as little design as possible. Good design is thorough, down to the last detail.&rdquo; <a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ob_GX50Za6c">Said Steve Jobs</a>, which resonates with me because I appreciate the idea of technology augmenting human, other than <a href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/6/24/5835708/google-x-labs-artificial-intelligence-elon-musk-terminator">mimicking</a> human.<a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>Ben Thompson&rsquo;s excellent new <a href="http://stratechery.com/2014/games-good-enough/">piece</a> about game consoles is on Stratechery, my daily read.<a href="#fnref:3" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
