<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: cook | ARTIFACT]]></title>
  <link href="http://kailun-wu.github.io/blog/categories/cook/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kailun-wu.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-29T16:34:49-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://kailun-wu.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kailun Wu]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Low GI Diet]]></title>
    <link href="http://kailun-wu.github.io/blog/low-GI-diet/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-01T17:45:13-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://kailun-wu.github.io/blog/low-GI-diet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I dropped 8 kg this summer (64 kg now) by <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Atkins_diet">Atkins diet</a> and running. The basic idea is quit eating starch to force myself into consuming body fat while using a scale to keep me motivated. I saw this worked on a college roommate two years ago and decided to take some effort to control my own body this time.</p>

<p>Is it painful? Yes, I was literally starving like never before! It&rsquo;s only after one week did I become used to that state and cannot feel too hungry. At some point I even felt clean, comfortable and not demanding. Eating less also made me appreciate the food more and save time on cooking.</p>

<p>You can find recipes and debates on Atkins diet online so I&rsquo;m not going to replicate anything. What&rsquo;s worth saying are the nicest foods I discovered that keep you full while having low calories and low GI<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Papaya: what a gift! Cut it into two half, clean the seeds and eat it with a spoon. Unbelievably easy and satisfying.</p></li>
<li><p>Strawberries: one box is enough for dinner, too acid sometimes, easy to get bored. Same goes for kiwifood.</p></li>
<li><p>Steamed pumpkin: has relatively high GI but satisfying nonetheless.</p></li>
<li><p>Miso soup: fast and delicious enough. Boil: peeled tomatoes, miso paste, sesame oil, diced tofu. Optional: shredded Napa cabbage, diced low-calorie ham, seaweed, shrimp. Topped with minced scallion after boiling.</p></li>
<li><p>Starbucks Green Tea Frappuccino w/ cream and w/o sugar: Fantastic! Diet drinks doesn&rsquo;t have to suck.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Plus, any stir-fries are edible as long as no sugar is added. Shredded pork with green pepper is one of <a href="http://www.xiachufang.com/cook/100963158/cooked/">my best practiced Sichuan recipes</a>. Salad with low-calorie dressing and without corns or bread was my choice of meal. But it&rsquo;s cold, acid and harsh so you don&rsquo;t want it too often.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Low <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Glycemic_index">GI</a> diet is essential to keep you consuming body fat.<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
