<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: apple | Minimaluminiumalism]]></title>
  <link href="http://kailun-wu.github.io/blog/categories/apple/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kailun-wu.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-04-01T15:27:13-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://kailun-wu.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kailun Wu]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thoughts on HealthKit - Not Really]]></title>
    <link href="http://kailun-wu.github.io/blog/thoughts-on-healthkit-not-really/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-12T01:38:31-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://kailun-wu.github.io/blog/thoughts-on-healthkit-not-really</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Watching <a href="https://developer.apple.com/videos/wwdc/2014/?id=203">a WWDC session video</a> on HealthKit, I&rsquo;m more than sure that leading technology companies won&rsquo;t be born in China or India, unless they&rsquo;ve mastered how to design great OS, frameworks, and even hardware-software integration.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> It&rsquo;s because in the end, users are using services in apps on OSes. Without the support from the OS and APIs, nowhere can innovation of apps, services and peripherals take roots. Apple is wielding so much power because they own most of the stuff they need. For example, how health data is saved and used on the iPhone is <a href="https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/#healthkit">defined in HealthKit</a> by Apple, rather than by Jawbone or data miners.</p>

<p>Right now, major OSes are owned by American companies and the key people involved are in America. All other attempts like BB 10, WebOS and MeeGo are largely failed. Building another OS is hard, because it depends on too much: timing, OS, developers, users and hardware.</p>

<p>Though hardware have been evolving much faster than software, it&rsquo;s possible that content, internet services and cloud will outweigh OS and devices. Maybe OS will be what we take for granted and radical innovation doesn&rsquo;t require much from the underlying layer.<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> Maybe the value and money will move towards being OS-agnostic, as is seen in Google, Facebook, and online advertisement. And that&rsquo;s why Amazon phone is not a necessity for Amazon itself. For now our world of devices and services is not a zero-sum game, but future awaits to be seen.</p>

<p>So much for the mumble. Showing opinions on the internet is cheap. I should resume the video now. :S</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>The city of Shenzhen becomes more and more interesting as a hardware heaven. See <a href="http://www.economist.com/news/special-report/21593590-why-southern-china-best-place-world-hardware-innovator-be-hacking">Hacking Shenzhen</a> from The Economist.<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>It&rsquo;s amazing how much layers of abstraction we&rsquo;ve made: from transistors to bits to softwares to ecosystems. Kevin Kelly&rsquo;s description on life and evolution is manifested in the world of bits again: autonomous entities form groups, abstraction emerges from groups, abstractions on top of abstractions.<a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[September 2014 Apple Keynote Take-on]]></title>
    <link href="http://kailun-wu.github.io/blog/sept-2013-apple-keynote-take-on/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-11T12:35:29-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://kailun-wu.github.io/blog/sept-2013-apple-keynote-take-on</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m sad to know the absence of new 4-inch models. Where&rsquo;re the 4-inch iPhones for the rest of us? The stasis on screen size during the 4-inch era and the sudden transition to 4.7-inch and 5.5-inch are not the optimal roadmap, unless Apple are quite confident about the mainstream adoption of 4.7-inch this time. Anyway, people who love 4-inch should be able to get a top-notch iPhone every year, right?</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned data-instgrm-version="4" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"><div style="padding:8px;"> <div style=" background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;"> <div style=" background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;"></div></div> <p style=" margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;"> <a href="https://instagram.com/p/vJXAjSPQDo/" style=" color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;" target="_top">不能忍，iPhone 6 太大太丑怎么办，索尼大法？ Dear Apple, iPhone 6 is so fucked up and huge that I don&#39;t know what else to use.</a></p> <p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;">A photo posted by @kailunwu on <time style=" font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;" datetime="2014-11-08T16:56:46+00:00">Nov 8, 2014 at 8:56am PST</time></p></div></blockquote>


<script async defer src="//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js"></script>


<p><br>
On the watch: fundamentally, why do I have to bear with the complexity of managing yet another device? <a href="http://stratechery.com/2014/apple-watch-asking-saying/">The lack of explaining</a> on why it needs to exist made the keynote less compelling.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> Tim Cook never talk about the incentives and human factors as much <a href="http://longform.org/stories/playboy-interview-steve-jobs">as Steve did</a> because liberal arts seem not so innate to Tim.</p>

<p>Apple is more capable of developing system and applications now.<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> This is more evident on the new watch. The original iPhone and iPad came with limited features, and the delay of OS X Leopard was caused by developing that very iPhone. But the apps and services on the watch are abundant on day one. Only the hardware definitely needs more iterations. I can&rsquo;t wait for <a href="http://www.hi-id.com/?p=2639">the iPhone-4-equivalent</a> of it because I&rsquo;m even more extreme than Braun on minimal and angular chassis.</p>

<p>Seriously, Jony Ive should leave icons alone! Icons in iOS 8 are still overly saturated and arbitrary to me. The only applicable wallpapers to me on iOS are limited to dark ones because of the vibrancy of app icons. We&rsquo;ve seen Apple design went extreme and weird before returning to rational. Hopefully it&rsquo;ll happen to iOS icons as well, quickly.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>In <a href="http://exponent.fm/episode-017-lets-end-it-there-updated/">the 17th episode</a> of Exponent, Ben Thompson said that the lack of reasoning and the massive amount of features may indicate a lack of clear sense on the watch within Apple. To consumers, too much features dilute the <em>essential</em> functions that makes the new category compelling.<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>[Update in Jan 2015] Well it turns out that, though Yosemite has been nearly flawless since its debut, iOS 8 is probably the most buggy .0 release ever.<a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
